mbc.com 2011-12-18

# Privacy Policy: Holland & Knight LLP

                                           Privacy Policy:
                                      Holland & Knight LLP
Welcome to hklaw.com, the Web site for Holland & Knight LLP ("H&K"). We are committed to
maintaining the privacy of information that you might share with us while visiting our site and
interacting with us online. This privacy policy and agreement (the "Privacy Policy" or "Policy")
covers how we collect, use, and treat personal information that you may provide through the
hklaw.com Web site (the "Web site" or the "Site") or while participating in exchanges via our
Extranet Sites.
The terms “you” and “your” refer to any visitor to the Web site, including (i) casual visitors to our
Site, who wish to learn more about our services ("Site Visitors"); (ii) clients and others who
choose to subscribe to our publications, and to receive announcements and other information
from our Site ("Information Recipients"); and (iii) clients of H&K, co-counsel, and others for
whom we have created, and granted access to, password-protected extranet sites ("Extranet
Users"). The terms “we” and “us” refer to Holland & Knight LLP, and the term "hklaw.com"
refers to our Web site. For your convenience, Section 17 provides a full set of definitions used
in this Privacy Policy.
1.       Your Consent
Please read this Privacy Policy carefully; when you consent to this Policy's terms, it creates
legal obligations on you and on H&K. We ask you to show your consent to the terms of this
Privacy Policy in different ways, depending on your relationship to the Site. The procedures for
consenting to this Policy are (a) less formal if you are a casual Site Visitor, and (b) more formal
if you are seeking to become an Information Recipient or an Extranet User.
         1.1.     Consent by Site Visitors. By accessing and using our Web site as a Site
         Visitor, you are acknowledging that you have read and understood this Privacy Policy
         and agree to be legally bound by it. If you do not agree with the terms of this Privacy
         Policy, please refrain from using our Site.
         1.2.     Consent by Information Recipients. If you register to become an Information
         Recipient via our Web site, you will be prompted to click an "I Accept" button linked to
         this Policy during the registration process. Clicking "I Accept" further confirms your
         agreement to be bound by this Privacy Policy.
         1.3.     Consent by Extranet Users. If you register to obtain access to an Extranet Site
         we have made available to you, you will similarly be prompted to click an "I Accept"
         button linked to this Policy during the registration process. Clicking "I Accept" further
         confirms your agreement to be bound by this Privacy Policy.
         1.4.     Connection to Our Web site Terms. Clicking the "I Accept" button will also
         confirm your agreement to comply our Web site Terms, including our "Code of Conduct,"
         as further specified during the registration process.
2.       Components Of Our hklaw.com Web site
                                                    1

Our Web site is divided into two broad areas and feature-sets: (i) those areas and features that
are accessible to all Users (the "General Site"); and (ii) those areas and features that are
password-protected, and that are designed to be available only to our Extranet Users (the
"Extranet Sites"), as further described below:
        2.1.      Our General Site. Our General Site is designed to provide Users with a range of
        information concerning (i) the services we offer; (ii) our attorneys and their experience;
        (iii) the geographic and legal subject matter areas in which we practice; (iv) employment
        opportunities; and (v) other materials concerning our firm. On our General Site, for
        example, Users can request newsletters, and other updates from our various practice
        groups. Our General Site is also designed to provide a gateway to the Extranet Sites
        that we set up for specific projects.
        2.2.      Our Extranet Sites. Our Extranet Sites are designed to provide a range of
        features, tailored to the particular H&K-Extranet User relationship. For example, in a
        litigation matter, we may set up an Extranet Site to provide a convenient method to
        share with our client (and potentially with co-counsel) case developments; scheduling
        events (such as hearing dates, depositions dates, and discovery deadlines) and
        information and work product. In a transaction, we may set up an Extranet Site to post
        due diligence materials, and other information to assist the H&K and client teams in
        working together. There are a range of other uses for Extranet Sites, that we develop
        and implement with our clients on a case-by-case basis.
3.      The Relationship Between This Policy And Applicable Ethics Rules
We have taken efforts to harmonize this Privacy Policy with ethics rules, and other rules that
apply to our legal practice ("Ethics Rules"). If a circumstance arises where applicable Ethics
Rules conflict with this Privacy Policy, then applicable Ethics Rules will govern our relationship,
and not the conflicting portion of this Privacy Policy.
4.      The Types Of Information You May Provide
Information you may provide while visiting our Site or while participating as an Information
Recipient or Extranet User falls into three broad categories: (i) Personal Information; (ii)
information concerning the matter that is the subject of the Extranet Site; and (iii) aggregate
information. We use the term “Personal Information” to mean any information you provide to
us over the Site that could reasonably be used to identify you, including your name, address, e-
mail address, birth date, telephone number or any combination of such information that could be
used to identify you. We use the term "Extranet Information" to refer to information you may
provide in connection with your authorized use of an Extranet Site. “Anonymous Information”
is information that does not identify you, and may include statistical information concerning, for
example, the pages on our Site that users visit most frequently.
5.      Our Uses Of The Information You Provide
We use Information you provide to us via the Web site only as provided in this Policy. First, we
use the Personal Information you provide via the Web site only for purposes of providing you
information concerning H&K and for otherwise responding to requests you may make, as
permitted by our Web site. We do not share your Personal Information with any third parties
(except as provided in Section 9 (Disclosures to Third Parties)). Second, we use the Extranet
Information you provide only for purposes of providing the H&K services that are the subject of
                                                   2

the associated Extranet Site (again, except as provided in Section 9 (Disclosures to Third
Parties)).
Specifically, we collect, or receive, information from Site Visitors, Information Recipients, and
Extranet Users at different points on our Web site, and use this information as follows:
        5.1.     Registration Information. In order to become an Information Recipient or an
        Extranet User on our Site, we require that you complete a registration form. This form
        asks for contact information, which includes such items as (i) name; (ii) mailing address;
        and (iii) e-mail address. We use this information to provide our Information Recipients
        with materials, as outlined below. For Extranet Users, we use the information to provide
        a password, and in part to authenticate the User as part of the process of providing
        access to an Extranet Site.
        5.2.     E-mail Addresses. We use your e-mail address to send newsletters,
        announcements concerning H&K or legal developments, notifications, and other
        information relating to our Site. In addition, we may use your e-mail address to invite
        you to presentations, or other functions we believe may be of interest to you. You will
        have the ability to opt out of receiving these materials, as provided in Section 10
        (Changing or Removing Information; Opting Out).
        5.3.     Informational Notices and Bulletins. Periodically, we may choose to send
        news, bulletins, or other information to Users, and will use Personal Information to send
        such communications. If we choose to undertake such communications, you will have
        the ability to opt out of receiving these communications as provided in Section 10
        (Changing or Removing Information; Opting Out).
        5.4.     Surveys. Periodically, we may initiate surveys at hklaw.com, and we may
        request Personal Information from you in connection with such surveys. You are free to
        choose whether you participate in this type of survey. The information we request may
        include contact information (such as name and e-mail address). Survey information will
        be used for purposes of monitoring or improving, and services we provide. We will notify
        you of relevant details in connection with asking for you participation in such surveys.
        5.5.     Extranet Exchanges. Where you provide us with Extranet Information, we use
        that Information only for purposes of fulfilling the services called for by the associated
        Extranet Site, and we do not share this Extranet Information with third parties (unless the
        Extranet Site provides for such sharing, or unless you consent). Where exchanges over
        an Extranet Site constitute attorney-client communications or attorney work product, we
        hold such information in confidence in accordance with applicable Ethics Rules.
6.      Anonymous, Aggregate Information.
We use Anonymous Information to analyze the effectiveness of our Site, and for other similar
purposes. In addition, from time to time, we may undertake or commission statistical and other
summary analyses of the general behavior and characteristics of Users of the Site, and may
share Anonymous Information with third parties for this purpose. Rest assured, though, that
Anonymous Information provided to third parties will not allow anyone to identify you, or
determine anything personal about you. We may collect Anonymous Information through
features of the software that supports our Site, through cookies, and through other means
described below.
                                                   3

        6.1.    IP Addresses; Logs. We may automatically receive and record information in
        our server logs from your browser, including your IP address (the Internet address of
        your PC), your computer's name, the type and version of your Web browser, referrer
        addresses, where the computer is routing from, and other generally-accepted log
        information. We may also record page views (hit counts) and other general statistical
        and tracking information, which will be aggregated with that of other users in order to
        understand how our Web site is being used, and for security and monitoring purposes.
        6.2.    Cookies. A cookie is a small amount of data, which often includes an
        anonymous unique identifier, which is sent to your browser from a Web site's computers
        and stored on your computer's hard drive. Cookies can be used to provide you with a
        tailored user experience and to make it easier for you to use a Web site upon a future
        visit. We may include cookies on our Web site and use them to recognize you when you
        return to our Web site. You may set your browser so that it does not accept cookies.
        Cookies must be enabled on your web browser, however, if you wish to access certain
        personalized features of our Services.
        6.3.    Tags. We may use so-called "pixel tags," which are small graphic images (also
        know as "Web beacons", "single-pixel GIFS", or "Web bugs"),to tell us what parts of our
        Web site have been visited, to measure the effectiveness of searches customers
        perform on our Site, and for other purposes. Pixel tags also enable us to send e-mail
        messages in a format Users can read, and they inform us whether e-mails have been
        opened, to help ensure that our messages are of interest to our Information Recipients
        and others. None of this data includes Personal Information, and you can "opt-out" of
        receiving these types of e-mails from us by following the directions provided in Section
        10 (Changing or Removing Information; Opting Out). If any Personal Information is
        collected using such tools, it will be subject to the terms of this Privacy Policy.
        6.4.    Click-Throughs. We may send e-mail messages which use a “click-through
        URL” linked to content on our Web site. When you click one of these URLs, you pass
        through our Web server before arriving at the destination web page. We track this click-
        through data to help determine Users' interest in particular topics and measure the
        effectiveness of our customer communications. If you prefer not to be tracked simply do
        not click text or graphic links in the e-mail, or notify us in accordance with Section 10
        (Changing or Removing Information; Opting Out).
7.      Any Information Linked With Your Personal Information Is Protected As “Personal
        Information”
To enable us to better understand the characteristics of our Users and to provide information
tailored to your needs, we may link (a) the Personal Information you have provided with (b)
Anonymous Information. If we combine or link any Anonymous Information or other information
with your Personal Information, the resulting combination will be treated and protected as
Personal Information under this Privacy Policy.
8.      The Relationship Between Information You Provide At Our Site, And Information
        From Offline Sources
This Privacy Policy applies to information that you provide through using our Web site. This
Privacy Policy does not apply to information you provide to H&K through other means.
                                                   4

9.      Disclosures To Third Parties
As an exception to the policies set out in Section 5 (Our Uses of the Information You Provide),
we will disclose your Personal Information to third parties without your express consent in the
following circumstances:
        9.1.     Site Vendors. We may employ other companies to perform functions on our
        behalf, such as maintaining the Web site, providing services related to the Site,
        collecting information, responding to and sending electronic mail, or other functions
        necessary to our business. In order to obtain these services, we may need to share your
        Personal Information with these companies (collectively, "Site Vendors"). We will
        provide Site Vendors with only that information necessary to perform their duties with
        respect to our Web site, and we do not allow them to use your Personal Information for
        any other purpose.
        9.2.     Questions of Harm; Legal. We may reveal your Personal Information on a
        case-by-case basis in order to comply with applicable Ethics Rules.
        9.3.     Extranet Information. Certain Extranet Sites may allow access and use by
        parties in addition to H&K and you (collectively, "Additional Extranet Users"). If you
        disclose information to Additional Extranet Users, this Policy does not cover the uses to
        which those Users may put the information, and H&K is not responsible for such Users'
        conduct. You should check the Privacy Policies of these Additional Extranet Users, or
        otherwise assure yourself that they provide the desired level of protection to your
        Personal and other Information, before making a disclosure.
10.     Changing or Removing Information; Opting Out.
        10.1. Discretionary Account Information. To allow appropriate control over
        Personal Information, you can access your account (after supplying your user name and
        password) to change your password, or to correct your e-mail address for errors.
        10.2. Opt-Out. If we send to you bulletins, updates, or other communications, we will
        provide you with the ability to decline -- or “opt-out of” – receiving such communications.
        Instructions for opting-out will be provided either (a) with each such communication, or
        (b) in a prominent location on our Web site. Please understand that you will not be
        allowed to "opt–out" of formal notices concerning operation of this Web site, and legal
        and other related notices concerning your relationship to the Site.
        10.3. Deleting Information Provided Via This Web site. Finally, if you have
        provided us with Personal Information in connection with your use of this Site, upon your
        request, we will remove this Personal Information from our Web site databases. Please
        understand, however, that it may be impossible to remove this information completely,
        due to backups and records of deletions. In addition, please understand that, if you
        request deletion of your information, you will be unable to utilize associated features of
        the Web site and any associated Services. You may not remove de-identified,
        anonymous, or aggregate data from our databases.
        10.4. Limitations on Deleting Information. Please keep in mind that this Privacy
        Policy applies only to information provided through this Web site, and does not apply to
        "Non-Web site Information," which is information H&K obtains or is provided via other
                                                   5

        channels, such as public databases. Therefore, if we remove information from our Web
        site databases in accordance with Section 10.3 (Deleting Information Provided Via This
        Web site), this will not remove Non-Web site Information from our databases. We will
        retain this Non-Web site Information in our databases, including Personal Information
        that may relate to our users, where applicable law permits us to retain the Information.
        If you have questions concerning Non-Web site Information, you may contact us as
        provided in Section 17 (Contact Us).
11.     Disclaimers
        11.1. Concerning Site Functionality And Availability. H&K does not promise that
        the Web site, including any Extranet Sites, will be error-free or uninterrupted, or that the
        Site will provide specific results from your use of any content, search, or link on the Site.
        Extranet Users acknowledge that they have means other than the Extranet Site available
        to them to obtain needed information from H&K and agree that, if H&K provides timely
        information via such other means, the inaccessibility of the Extranet Site is harmless.
        H&K DISCLAIMS ALL EXPRESS OR IMPLIED WARRANTIES (INCLUDING ANY
        IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY AND FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR
        PURPOSE) WITH RESPECT TO THE FUNCTIONALITY OR AVAILABILITY OF THE
        SITE.
        11.2. Advisory; No Legal Advice Provided Via The General Site. The information
        presented on the General Site is provided as a courtesy by H&K. The General Site is
        not intended a substitute for professional legal advice. If you have, or suspect that you
        may have a legal problem, you should consult your lawyer to obtain legal information
        and recommendations specific to your problem,. H&K EXPRESSLY DISCLAIMS ANY
        REPRESENTATION OR WARRANTY EXPRESS OR IMPLIED CONCERNING THE
        ACCURACY, COMPLETENESS OR FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE OF
        THE INFORMATION CONTAINED ON THE GENERAL SITE. Persons accessing this
        information assume full responsibility for the use of the information and understand and
        agree that H&K is not responsible or liable for any claim, loss or damage arising from the
        use of the information.
        11.3. Scope of Disclaimers. H&K expressly retains, and does not disclaim in any
        manner, responsibility for the content of attorney-client communications via Extranet
        Sites, and its provision of any advice or attorney work product to its clients via the
        Extranet Sites.
        11.4. Use of Web site Does Not Create An Attorney-Client Relationship. You
        agree that your use of our Web site does not create an attorney-client relationship.
12.     Security
We have put in place security systems designed to prevent unauthorized access to or
disclosure of Personal Information and Extranet Information you may provide to us, and we take
all reasonable steps to secure and safeguard this Information. Our site's Password-Protected
Areas require Users to give us unique identifiers such as their user id and password. Employees
of H&K (and employees of our Site Vendors) are required to acknowledge that they understand
and will abide by our policies with respect to the confidentiality of Personal Information, and
Extranet Information.
                                                   6

Our security systems are therefore structured to deter and prevent hackers and others from
accessing information you provide to us. We also use software programs to monitor network
traffic to identify unauthorized attempts to upload or change information, or otherwise cause
damage. Please understand, though, that this information should not be construed in any way
as giving business, legal, or other advice, or warranting as fail proof, the security of information
provided by or submitted to our Site. Due to the nature of Internet communications and evolving
technologies, we cannot provide, and disclaim, assurance that the information you provide us
will remain free from loss, misuse, or alteration by third parties who, despite our efforts, obtain
unauthorized access.
13.      Notice of Security Incident
If we detect, despite the safeguards set out above, an intrusion or other unauthorized access to
or use of Personal Information (an "Intrusion"), we will (i) notify effected users of the Intrusion if
the information at issue is sensitive, as determined by law, (ii) deliver this notice by the means
we deem most efficient under the circumstances (such as, for example, first class mail or e-
mail); (iii) use contact information for each effected user that is current in our files; and (iv) use
commercially reasonable efforts to accomplish these steps and effect this notice in a timely
manner. To the extent applicable law requires steps in addition to those specified above, we will
under all circumstances comply with applicable law.
14.      Notification of Changes
From time to time, we may change its Privacy Policy. If we make any changes regarding
disclosure of Personal Information to third parties, upon your next login we will inform you of the
modified policy. We will post notice of the new Policy from the privacy link on our Web site. With
respect to Site Visitors, your use of our Site following any such change constitutes your
agreement to follow and be bound by the Privacy Policy, as changed. With respect to
Information Recipients and Extranet Users, no such changes will take effect unless and until
you have provided us with your consent to such changes, in accordance with Section 1 (Your
Consent), above.
15.      Relationship to Terms of Use and Other Contracts
This Privacy Policy must be read in conjunction with our Terms of Use, and the provisions of our
Terms of Use are incorporated herein. To the extent the Terms of Use conflict with the terms of
this Privacy Policy, the terms of this Privacy Policy will control.
16.      Participation by Children and Teens; Advisory
Our Web site is not directed at children, and we will not accept or request Personal Information
from individuals we know to be under 13. In accordance with the Children’s Online Privacy
Protection Act ("COPPA"), if we learn that a child under 13 has provided personally identifiable
information, we will either (i) delete this information from our databases, in accordance with our
deletion procedures, set out in Section 10, or (ii) obtain verifiable parental consent, in
accordance with COPPA.
17.      Definitions
         17.1. “Anonymous Information” has the meaning provide in Section 4 (The Types
         of Information You May Provide).
                                                    7

         17.2. "Ethics Rules" has the meaning provided in Section 3 (The Relationship
         Between This Policy And Applicable Ethics Rules).
         17.3. "Extranet Information" has the meaning set out in Section 4 (The Types of
         Information You May Provide).
         17.4. "Extranet Site" means a set of Web pages, separated from the Web site, and
         designed to be inaccessible to any Site Users other than those with the proper password
         to the pages. The term "Extranet Site" is further defined in Section 2.2 (Our Extranet
         Sites).
         17.5. "Extranet User" means an H&K client, co-counsel with H&K, or other user for
         whom H&K has created, and granted access to, an Extranet Site.
         17.6. "Information User" means an H&K client or other person who chooses to
         subscribe to publications, or receive announcements and other information, from our
         Site.
         17.7. "Password-Protected Area" means that area or those areas of the Site where,
         in order to obtain access, a user must provide a password. Unless otherwise indicated,
         Password-Protected Areas consist of our Extranet Sites.
         17.8. "Personal Information" means a natural person's name, mailing address, e-mail
         address, telephone number, cell phone number, and other information by which that
         person can be identified.
         17.9.    "Privacy Policy" means the Web site privacy policy, located at www.hklaw.com.
         17.10. "Site Visitor" means a casual visitor to the Web site, who does not seek to
         become an Information Recipient, or does not qualify as an Extranet User.
         17.11. "Terms of Use" or "Terms" means the Web site terms of use, located at
         www.hklaw.com.
         17.12. "User" means a Site Visitor, Information Recipient, Extranet User, or .
         17.13. “You” and “you” refer to any User of the Web site.
18.      Site Administration
If you have comments or questions about the administration of this Site, you may contact us at
the following addresses:
         Webmaster (at) hklaw (dot) com
19.      Effective Date
The effective date of this Privacy Policy is October 5, 2007.
                                                  8

COPYRIGHT AND LEGAL NOTICE.
Copyright ©2007 Holland & Knight LLP. All Rights Reserved.
                                             9

Table (for convenience)
1.        Your Consent .................................................................................................................... 1
2.        Components Of Our hklaw.com Web site ......................................................................... 1
3.        The Relationship Between This Policy And Applicable Ethics Rules ................................ 2
4.        The Types Of Information You May Provide ..................................................................... 2
5.       Our Uses Of The Information You Provide ....................................................................... 2
6.        Anonymous, Aggregate Information.................................................................................. 3
7.        Any Information Linked With Your Personal Information Is Protected As
          “Personal Information”....................................................................................................... 4
8.        The Relationship Between Information You Provide At Our Site, And Information
         From Offline Sources ........................................................................................................ 4
9.       Disclosures To Third Parties ............................................................................................. 5
10.      Changing or Removing Information; Opting Out. .............................................................. 5
11.      Security ............................................................................................................................. 6
12.      Notice of Security Incident ................................................................................................ 7
13.      Notification of Changes ..................................................................................................... 7
14.      Relationship to Terms of Use and Other Contracts .......................................................... 7
15.      Participation by Children and Teens; Advisory ................................................................. 7
16.      Definitions ......................................................................................................................... 7
17.      Contact Us ........................................................................................................................ 8
18.      Effective Date.................................................................................................................... 8
# 4796387_v3
                                                                   10
